[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
Ooh, I love it when
me two best gals become
哦，我喜欢当
我成为两个最好的女孩
me two best paying customers.
我是两个付费最高的客户。
Sit tight.
Lunch is almost ready.
坐稳。
午餐快准备好了。
Order up!
赶快下单吧！
- Uh...
- Oh!
- 呃...
- 哦！
Let me get a southwestern patty,
给我一份西南馅饼
heavy on the south.
南方重。
- No, wait!
- Uh...
- 不，等等！
- 呃...
[laughs]
[笑]
[exclaiming]
[惊呼]
Ooh, feels like Mrs. Puff!
哦哦，感觉像泡芙夫人！
Hi, Mrs. Puff.
嗨，普芙女士。
[laughs]
[笑]
Ugh.
啊。
Remember, SpongeBob, we agreed:
请记住，海绵宝宝，我们同意：
outside of class,
we don't know each other.
课外，
我们互相不认识。
Oh, yeah!
哦，是啊！
Well, here's your Krabby Patty,
mysterious lady.
好吧，这是你的蟹肉饼，
神秘的女士。
[popping]
[爆裂声]
[squirts, pops]
[喷射，流行音乐]
"Eye" hope you enjoy your meal.
“眼睛”希望您用餐愉快。
[laughs]
[笑]
[ominous music]
[不祥的音乐]
[gasps]
The health inspector?
[喘气]
卫生督察？
But I already bribed him
this year.
但我已经贿赂了他
今年。
[device beeps]
- Mm-hmm.
[设备蜂鸣声]
- 嗯嗯。
Mm-hmm.
嗯嗯。
Just as I feared.
正如我所担心的那样。
Someone in this restaurant is infected
这家餐厅有人被感染
with the highly contagious
clam flu.
具有高度传染性
蛤流感。
You're all under quarantine.
你们都在隔离中。
[device pings]
[设备 ping]
Hmm.
唔。
[all yelling]
[大家大喊]
- [grunting]
- Ahh!
- [咕哝]
- 啊！
[yelling]
Oh!
[大喊]
哦！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Wait.
What's a "corn-a-bean"?
等待。
A quarantine is like
a mandatory sleepover,
隔离就像
强制性过夜，
and we're all invited.
我们都被邀请了。
both: Sleepover!
Sleepover!
两人：过夜！
过夜！
[air horn blares]
[both shriek]
[两人都尖叫]
A quarantine means
you're locked in here
检疫手段
你被锁在这里了
with a sick person until
we're all sick and miserable.
我们都生病了，都很痛苦。
[gasping]
[喘气]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Well, I'm aborting
Operation Soda Jerk.
嗯，我要放弃了
苏打混蛋行动。
Communicable diseases are
my cue to leave.
传染性疾病是
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[laughs]
[笑]
Quarantine, shmorantine.
检疫，shmorantine。
I'm the great... ahh!
我是伟大的……啊！
Breach contained!
违规已被遏制！
Good work.
干得好。
[moaning]
[呻吟]
[gulps]
Maybe we should stay inside.
[吞咽]
也许我们应该呆在里面。
But I have to cheer
at the big game tomorrow.
但我必须欢呼
在明天的大型比赛中。
Everyone's gonna laugh at me
if I get sick and die first.
每个人都会笑我
如果我先生病死了。
Oh, not to worry,
me massive, little angel.
哦，不用担心，
We'll just do what we did
in me old navy days.
我们就做我们做过的事
在我过去的海军时代。
Ooh, old navy days.
哦，旧海军时代。
You see, first,
we found the sicko,
你看，首先，
我们找到了病人，
and then we just locked 'em
in the freezer-o.
然后我们就把它们锁起来
With the infected sailor isolated,
随着被感染的水手被隔离，
the rest of us could
enjoy ourselves,
我们其他人可以
享受我们自己，
certain of our continued
good health.
确定我们继续
身体健康。
[sighs]
Good times.
[叹气]
美好时光。
You let them out of the freezer
你把它们从冰箱里拿出来
once they were better, right?
一旦他们变得更好，对吧？
Huh?
啊？
I suppose someone
let 'em out... eventually.
让他们出去……最终。
Okay.
[laughs]
好的。
[笑]
Who's feeling queasy?
谁感觉不舒服？
Go ahead now, raise your hand.
现在继续，举起你的手。
[crickets chirp]
[蟋蟀鸣叫]
So that's how
you wanna play it, eh?
所以就是这样
你想玩吗？
Fine.
美好的。
I'll examine all of ya for signs
我会检查你们所有人是否有迹象
of the pestilence meself!
瘟疫本身！
Oh, no!
哦，不！
I am not letting any of you
我不会让你们任何人
infected imbeciles near me.
我附近被感染的低能儿。
I'm... oh!
我是……哦！
[grunts, sniffs]
[咕哝声，嗅嗅]
[sneezes]
[all whimper]
[打喷嚏]
[全都呜咽]
He's the sick one.
He belongs in the freezer!
他属于冰箱里！
Get him!
- Ah!
抓住他！
- 啊！
Wait!
等待！
I'll go willingly.
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
I feel fine,
我感觉很好，
but I don't wanna risk
infecting my friends.
但我不想冒险
感染我的朋友。
Hmm?
唔？
Especially you, Squidward.
[smooches]
[亲吻]
[yells, panting]
[大喊，气喘吁吁]
[somber music]
[忧郁的音乐]
All I ask is that
you remember me as I was,
我所要问的是
你还记得我本来的样子
full of life...
充满生机……
Whew. - No!
呼。 - 不！
Oh, it sounds like
he's really suffering in there.
哦，听起来像
他在那里真的很痛苦。
Oh!
I can't bear to look.
哦！
我不忍心看。
Can someone describe it to me?
有人可以向我描述一下吗？
All right, come on now.
Come on.
好吧，现在就来吧。
快点。
Let the poor boy enjoy
his agony in peace.
让这个可怜的孩子享受
他的痛苦平静。
Whoo!
哇！
[laughing]
[笑]
Yow!
Oh!
哟！
哦！
[laughs]
[笑]
Yeah!
Whee!
是的！
哎哟！
Whoo!
呼！
Ooh, ice cream.
哦，冰淇淋。
Well, problem solved.
嗯，问题解决了。
Now we sit back and wait
for the all clear.
现在我们坐下来等待
为了一切都清楚。
Hmm?
唔？
Hey.
嘿。
[licking]
[舔]
Oh.
Ooh.
哦。
[all sigh]
[Patrick laughs]
[众人叹息]
[帕特里克笑]
Boy, I sure am feeling
under the leather.
男孩，我确实感觉
在皮革下面。
It's "weather," you moron,
and... ah!
这是“天气”，你这个白痴，
还有……啊！
Sweet Neptune!
甜蜜的海王星！
[moaning]
[呻吟]
The clam flu, it's spreading!
蛤流感，正在蔓延！
Into the freezer with him!
和他一起进冰箱！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Huh?
Hmm.
啊？
唔。
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
[both grunt]
[两人咕哝]
[squeals]
[尖叫声]
[sighs]
[叹气]
We'll just have to be
more vigilant now.
我们只需要做
现在更加警惕了。
Anyone could be a carrier.
任何人都可以成为携带者。
[hums]
[哼哼]
Itchy skin!
He's got clam flu!
皮肤痒！
他得了蛤流感！
What?
No, no, I was just scratching.
什么？
不不不，我只是在抓挠而已。
Freezer!
冰箱！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[huffing]
[气喘吁吁]
[sighs]
[叹气]
[yawns]
[哈欠]
Freezer!
冰箱！
[yelling]
[大喊]
Heh, at least we know
we're safe now,
呵呵，至少我们知道
我们现在安全了
me baby beluga.
我的白鲸宝宝。
[strained laugh]
[紧张的笑声]
Oh, I just remembered.
哦，我刚刚想起来了。
I didn't spend all your money
at the mall.
我没有花你所有的钱
在商场。
Here's your change.
这是你的零钱。
Change?
改变？
Oh, the disease must have addled
哦，这病一定是疯了
your tiny teenage mind!
你那幼小的心灵！
Wait!
I take it back.
等待！
我收回它。
There's still some shoes
I wanna buy!
还有一些鞋子
我想买！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[cheerful music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ La, la, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦啦啦啦♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ 啦，啦，啦，啦，啦 ♪
♪ La, la, la, la ♪
♪ 啦，啦，啦，啦 ♪
So let me get this straight.
所以让我说清楚。
Nobody in this freezer is
actually sick?
这个冰箱里没有人
真的生病了吗？
- Never felt better.
- I'm fine.
- 从未感觉好过。
- 我很好。
Ice cream!
冰淇淋！
Well, if no one's sick in here,
好吧 如果这里没有人生病的话
then the sick person must be...
那么这个病人一定是……
[gasps]
Daddy!
[喘气]
爸爸！
Oh, no!
- There, there.
哦，不！
- 那里，那里。
Oh, ah, oh!
哦，啊，哦！
I say we bust out of here,
grab Krabs,
我说我们离开这里
抢螃蟹，
and lock him away.
并把他锁起来。
Oh, yeah!- Daddy!
哦，是的！-爸爸！
Who's this now?
现在这个人是谁？
I don't know.
我不知道。
Mr. Krabs didn't tell us
to question his orders.
蟹老板没有告诉我们
质疑他的命令。
I'll just wait for him
to let me out.
我只会等他
让我出去。
You can't cook Krabby Patties
你不会煮蟹肉饼
if you're locked in the freezer.
如果你被锁在冰箱里。
All right, let's put
this crab on ice.
好吧，让我们把
这只螃蟹在冰上。
[all grunting]
[全都咕哝]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
You sickos are supposed to be
in the freezer!
你们这些病应该是
在冰箱里！
You're the sicko!
你就是那个病人！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[objects clang]
[物体叮当作响]
Stay away from me, you sickos!
离我远点，你们这些变态！
[yelps]
[尖叫声]
[groans]
[呻吟]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
For the good of all of us,
为了我们大家的利益，
you have to go into the freezer.
你必须进入冰箱。
Keep your filthy hands off me,
把你的脏手拿开我
you infected ingrate.
你感染了忘恩负义。
Oh, look.
Freedom!
哦，看。
自由！
[laughs]
[笑]
[grunts]
He's in the grease trap!
[咕哝]
他掉进了油脂陷阱里了！
Well, someone's gonna have
to fish him out
嗯，有人会有
把他捞出来
before he gets to the sewer
and infects the whole town!
在他到达下水道之前
并感染了整个城镇！
Hey, I can help!
嘿，我可以帮忙！
[grunts]
- [gasps]
[咕哝]
- [喘气]
[coughing]
- [grunting]
[咳嗽]
- [咕哝]
- Patrick. Patrick!
- Huh?
- 帕特里克.帕特里克！
- 啊？
There's full sized hatch
over here.
有全尺寸舱口
在这里。
Well, what do you know?
那么，你知道什么？
[yelps]
[尖叫声]
[gasps, coughs]
[喘气、咳嗽]
Eugene, are you in here?
尤金，你在这儿吗？
[gurgles]
[咯咯声]
[yells, coughs]
[喊叫、咳嗽]
Ah!
Sicko germs!
啊!
病菌！
[coughs]
Ah!
[咳嗽]
啊！
You can't catch me.
你抓不到我。
I'm too healthy
for all you sickos!
我太健康了
为了你们所有的病态！
[laughs]
[笑]
Daddy, stop!
爸爸，停下来！
[all gasp]
[全都喘气]
[snorts]
[哼哼]
[spits]
[吐口水]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
There's nowhere left to run.
无处可逃。
I'm not licked yet!
我还没被舔呢！
Oh, yeah?
哦，是吗？
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[growls]
[咆哮]
[grunts]
- [yelps]
[咕哝]
- [尖叫声]
Hey.
Hey!
嘿。
嘿！
SpongeBob!
海绵宝宝！
You'll never get me.
Ha-ha!
你永远得不到我。
哈哈！
[grunts, coughs]
[咕哝声、咳嗽声]
[yells]
[喊叫]
[both grunt]
[两人咕哝]
[yelling]
- [moaning]
[大喊]
- [呻吟]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[shrieks]
[尖叫声]
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
[yelping]
[尖叫]
Ah!
啊!
I got him!
我抓到他了！
[yells, grunts]
[喊叫，咕哝]
Ah!
Oh!
啊!
哦！
[all clamoring,
objects crashing]
[大家都在叫嚣，
物体崩溃]
[whistling]
[吹口哨]
[hums]
[哼哼]
Hmm, hello?
Anyone here?
嗯，你好？
这里有人吗？
[all groaning]
[全都呻吟]
Ha, funny story,
哈，有趣的故事，
um, I was holding my equipment
upside down yesterday.
嗯，我拿着我的装备
昨天颠倒了。
[laughs]
Nobody was actually sick.
[笑]
实际上没有人生病。
Ha!
Oh, what a goof.
哈!
哦，真是个傻瓜。
Huh?
[all groaning]
啊？
[全都呻吟]
Oh, my Neptune.
哦，我的海王星。
Grease gout.
油脂痛风。
- [moans]
- Moldy measles!
- [呻吟]
- 发霉的麻疹！
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
[groans]
[呻吟]
Trash trichinosis!
垃圾旋毛虫病！
[moans, coughing]
[呻吟、咳嗽]
Dust bunny bronchitis!
尘兔支气管炎！
[gasps, sneezes]
[喘气，打喷嚏]
Polyester plague!
涤纶瘟疫！
[gasps]
[喘气]
[retches, groans]
[干呕、呻吟]
The whole shebang!
整个shebang！
[yelps]
[尖叫声]
They're all sick!
他们都病了！
Ultra-mega quarantine!
超大规模隔离！
You heard him.
你听到他的声音了。
Get this disease-ridden
cesspit out of here!
得了这个病
粪坑离开这里！
Drop it somewhere safe,
把它扔到安全的地方，
somewhere no one ever goes...
没有人去过的地方...
[all moaning]
[全都呻吟]
What the...?
什么...？
No!
不！
I don't wanna get sick too.
我也不想生病。
Stay away! No!
走开！不！
[sneezes]
[打喷嚏]
Ah, barnacles.
啊，藤壶。